<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soren Bjornstad</title>
    <link>https://ap.sorenbjornstad.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ap.sorenbjornstad.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Soren Bjornstad's attopublish feed</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2022 Soren Bjornstad</copyright>
    <generator>attopublish</generator>
    <managingEditor>contact@sorenbjornstad.com (Soren Bjornstad)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>webmaster@sorenbjornstad.com (Soren Bjornstad)</webMaster>

    <item>
    <title>[6] Article: Searching for outliers (Ben Kuhn)</title>
    <author>contact@sorenbjornstad.com (Soren Bjornstad)</author>
    <category>Article</category>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 18:50:00 -0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#6</link>
    <guid>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#6</guid>
    <description>As explained in the popular consciousness by Nassim Nicholas Taleb, some things
are more or less evenly distributed and you can think about them in averages,
while other things are very unevenly distributed, to the point where only the
outliers matter. Kuhn usefully terms these “light-tailed” and “heavy-tailed”
distributions and points out that many if not most of the important
distributions in an individual’s life are heavy-tailed (jobs, romantic
relationships, business ideas, leisure activities, etc.). Then he explores
strategies for improving your chances of obtaining a good outcome from
heavy-tailed distributions in your life.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>[5] Quote</title>
    <author>contact@sorenbjornstad.com (Soren Bjornstad)</author>
    <category>Published</category>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 17:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#5</link>
    <guid>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#5</guid>
    <description>
      &lt;p&gt;
        One way I often like to think about behavioral questions is this: if everyone
followed in these footsteps, would it make the whole organization (or community)
overall better or worse?
      &lt;/p&gt;
        
      &lt;cite&gt;Sophie Alpert, “Yak Shaving and Fixing”, https://sophiebits.com/2018/12/03/yak-shaving-fixing.html&lt;/cite&gt;
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>[4] Published: Effective Flashcard Writing: Decomposing half a chapter of Thinking, Fast and Slow</title>
    <author>contact@sorenbjornstad.com (Soren Bjornstad)</author>
    <category>Published</category>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 17:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#4</link>
    <guid>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#4</guid>
    <description>I find it is often helpful to &lt;a
href=&quot;https://zettelkasten.sorenbjornstad.com/#WatchingExpertsUseSoftware&quot;&gt;watch
experts do things&lt;/a&gt;, whether they explain their thought process or not. In
this video, I make some spaced-repetition flashcards in RemNote and explain why
I&#x27;m making the choices I&#x27;m making.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>[3] Quote</title>
    <author>contact@sorenbjornstad.com (Soren Bjornstad)</author>
    <category>Published</category>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 17:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#3</link>
    <guid>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#3</guid>
    <description>
      &lt;p&gt;
        Has someone tried unplugging the United States and plugging it back in?
      &lt;/p&gt;
        
      &lt;cite&gt;sign in front of an independent computer shop in Lindstrom, &lt;/cite&gt;
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>[2] Published: Understanding the Long-Term Risks of Contraceptive Failure</title>
    <author>contact@sorenbjornstad.com (Soren Bjornstad)</author>
    <category>Published</category>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 17:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#2</link>
    <guid>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#2</guid>
    <description>Most people don&#x27;t have an intuitive understanding of how small risks add up over time.
    When sex, bad statistics, and bad public-health messaging are thrown into the mix,
    people end up making bad decisions.
    In this article, spreadsheet simulator, and demo video,
    we explore the chances of unintended pregnancy over a person&#x27;s lifetime
    – which are almost certainly higher than you think if you&#x27;re never looked into it –
    and what you can do to reduce them.
    (I got interested in this topic on a whim after reading a history of AIDS
     had me thinking constantly about sexual health messaging for about a solid week.)</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>[1] Announcement</title>
    <author>contact@sorenbjornstad.com (Soren Bjornstad)</author>
    <category>Article</category>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 17:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#1</link>
    <guid>https://pp.sorenbjornstad.com/#1</guid>
    <description>Since I quit regularly using most social media, I haven&#x27;t missed the ads or
political screaming one bit, but I have found I miss being able to easily share
random interesting things with the world. I&#x27;m hoping to resolve this and
recapture a bit of the energy of Web 1.0 by posting on a simple website
instead; perhaps a few people will still be interested enough to follow a
website or RSS feed (remember those? I still use them!). This weekend, I wrote
a tiny, &lt;a
href=&quot;https://controlaltbackspace.org/design/dreamdir-and-the-unix-philosophy-or-likable-software/&quot;&gt;likable&lt;/a&gt;
tool called attopublish to manage the posts, and I&#x27;ll tweak it as needed.
attopublish will also be available as an open-source tool sooner or later for
anyone who&#x27;s interested.</description>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
